William Setzer

william@setzer.tech · 334-300-7107 · linkedin.com/in/william-setzer Professional programmer | Python enthusiast | Problem solver

SUMMARY

Customer-focused professional with a passion for data science offering experience in computer programming, data collection, data processing, and analysis, with knowledge in Python, Golang, and Java.

Skills and Languages

- Strong knowledge of Python, Java, Golang, Linux
- Good knowledge of PostgreSQL
- Working knowledge of JavaScript, Ruby, and Scala
- · Beginner proficiency in German

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science with Honors, *Magna Cum Laude* University of Alabama at Birmingham GPA: 3.81

May 2018 Birmingham, Alabama

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

August 2021 – Present

BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA

SHIPT

• Used Python to ingest our partners' catalog data, later a combination of Python and Golang

- Helped to maintain and improve the data ingestion framework, introducing parallel and asynchronous processing
- Streamlined the onboarding process for new retail partners by creating a data mapping template for partners to fill out
- Managed running programs through Airflow and GCS Cloud Console
- Worked with AWS, GCS, and Kafka to move data between services
- Used Golang in my team's effort to replace and update our ingestion system
- Worked within my team to design new features and APIs
- Created and maintained robust unit and integration tests to ensure code works as expected before it ever runs on the server

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SENECA RESOURCES

May 2020 - August 2021

BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA

• Operated as a junior software developer at Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Alabama.

- Used a combination of Java, JavaScript, and HTML to maintain and add features to the myBlueCross website.
- Designed and implemented REST API endpoints in the Spring framework for Java.
- Wrote queries in SQL for IBM Db2 and integrated them into Spring with JDBC.
- Modernized the style of web pages according to specification using CSS and SCSS.
- Wrote test documents and unit tests in JUnit for new features.
- Collaborated with other developers to successfully coordinate changes.

Cyber Security Engineer

JUNE 2019 – MAY 2020

BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA

Regions Bank

- Redesigned content and processes to fit modern standards and development practices.
- Automated SOC processes with the Splunk Phantom platform.
- Created playbooks, automation scripts, and product integrations within Phantom.
- Integrated the SOAR platform with a range of products to provide automation actions for workflows.
- Migrated content from Demisto to Splunk's Phantom platform.

RESEARCH/TEACHING ASSISTANT

August 2017 – June 2019

UAB DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Birmingham, Alabama

• Collected data using Python, Ruby, and PostgreSQL from Reddit and alternative social media sites, e.g. 4chan, 8chan, Minds.

- Analyzed collected data with Python and Hadoop to find statistical patterns, producing plots to visualize the data using various plots, e.g. CDFs, CCDFs, joint distributions, and basic scatter and line plots.
- Used change point analysis to correlate changes in the patterns of data collected to real-world events.
- Instructed lab sections for both Introduction to Computer Science and Computer Architecture, teaching and assisting a wide variety of students as they learned Python in the introductory course and x86 Assembly in the computer architecture course.
- Graded homework assignments.

PROGRAMMING TEAM LEAD & PROGRAMMER

April 2017 – August 2018

UAB Computer Forensics Research Lab

BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA

- Supervised the programming team, ensuring the quality of code and the delivery of tools for use by the lab's cybercrime analysts.
- Established effective use of version control and documentation practices.
- Conducted programmer interviews and onboarded new team members.
- Created efficient web scrapers to scrape forums in **Python** using packages including *Requests*, *lxml*, *aiohttp*, *AsyncIO*, *multiprocessing*, and *Selenium*.
- Transitioned web scraping in the lab from pure Selenium to Requests, AsyncIO, and aiohttp to create faster web scrapers.
- Created a web forum database for scrapers in **PostgreSQL** to replace multiple non-standardized ways of storing forum data.
- Set up and maintained a MongoDB instance for collecting a variety of non-standard data collected from the web.

Barista
Starbucks

May 2016 – November 2016
Birmingham, Alabama

Cashier

January 2016 – May 2016

Chick-fil-A

Birmingham, Alabama

PROSTHETIC TECHNICIAN

ALABAMA ARTIFICIAL LIMB AND ORTHOTICS SERVICE

MAY 2013 – JUNE 2013, DECEMBER 2015 – JANUARY 2016

MONTGOMERY, ALABAMA

Website Product Entry
Beth's Heirloom Sewing

June 2014 – August 2014
Wetumpka, Alabama

Awards and Leadership

• UAB President's List Spring 2016, Fall 2016, Fall 2017, Spring 2018

• UAB Dean's List Fall 2015, Spring 2017

• UAB Presidential Scholarship Fall 2014 – Spring 2018

• Vermeer Corporation Scholarship 2014, 2016